OBJECTIVE

Current Software Development Engineer with particular interest in object-oriented programming. Extensive experience in object-oriented programming in Java/Python as well as full stack web development with Java Spring Boot, React/Node.js and SQL through coursework at Stony Brook University and work at Publicis Sapient. Additional experience with Cloud technologies in Google Cloud Platform, GitHub Actions, and Terraform. Google Cloud Associate Cloud Engineer certified.

EXPERIENCE

June 2021 - Current

Software Development Engineer, Publicis Sapient (August 2022 - Present)

- · Worked with Financial Services account, implementing cloud migration with GCP, Terraform and GitHub Actions based on client needs.
- · Implemented code pipeline automation in GitHub Actions and deployment management with GCP Cloud Run Services, in addition to containerizing and managing microservices through Docker & GCP Container Registry for large-scale Health Services client.
- · Collaborated with small internal team to create custom virtual workspaces focused on client experience using React-three-fiber and other
- · Consistent implementation of SCRUM principles throughout development processes, managing weekly/bi-weekly sprints using tools like Jira & Confluence, closely aligned with Agile methodology and best software engineering practices.
- · Member of the NYC Office Culture Committee, designed to foster community and office engagement through various in-person

Software Development Engineer Intern, Publicis Sapient (June - August 2021)

- · Collaborated with a group of interns and industry leads to build a full stack Chatbot and webpage for small business sector of a large-
- · Helped lead team, which included managing timelines, delegating certain tasks, and ensuring thorough and effective communication amongst team as-well-as with clients.
- · Worked with lead-engineers developing client's early-educational application, learning best programming practices and gaining hands-on experience with industry technology stack.

EDUCATION

August 2018 - May 2022

B.S. in Computer Science, Stony Brook University

- · Gained considerable experience with object-oriented programming and design, with heavy emphasis on Java & Python, as well as full stack web development.
- · Worked with MATLAB and math-heavy Python libraries including Numpy, Scikit-learn, TensorFlow, PyTorch, & Pandas on large language models and machine learning algorithms.
- · Experience with electrical and computer engineering through lab and additional coursework.
- · Maintained presidential scholarship for scholastic merit for all 8 semesters.

PROJECT WORK

· Full stack Redistricting Analyzer app:

- Collaborated with three other students to build web app for analyzing political districting plans and detecting gerrymandering, using live demographics derived from backend database.
- Ran algorithms on Seawulf supercomputer to determine fair metrics which were then used to compare with enacted plans for fairness measures.
- Used React.js for frontend featuring fully draggable/zoomable map and data visualization, Java Spring Boot backend integrated with MongoDB for server logic and data retrieval, as well as Seawulf supercomputer to run complex algorithms.

· Full stack Chatbot:

- Collaborated with five other interns to design & develop website and Chatbot using Java Spring Boot for backend server processing, React.js/Node.js for frontend/UI development, GCP Cloud SQL for data management, Google DialogFlow for functionality, & GCP App Engine for deployment.
- Managed multiple aspects of stack, with concentrated effort in server/client interaction and frontend design
- Helped to manage roles and delegate work amongst team.

· Full stack list app:

Built a list creator/manager application using React.js/JavaScript and Express.js integrated with MongoDB. Features password encryption and account creation with user management in database.

SKILLS & ABILITIES